Robert Fox

Sales and Business Development Manager - Enterprise Accounts - Experience from LinkedIn, DueDil, Totaljobs.com and The Guardian

London robertpfox1975@gmail.com 07738632304

Over the past 18+ years, I've had the pleasure of working at companies who are world leaders in their field including Indeed, LinkedIn, TotalJobs Group (Launched by Reed Elsevier), Guardian Media Group, and Transport for London- mainly within the internet, digital, social media and offline media environments.

In all previous roles, I've been responsible for new business generation, growing existing accounts, and delivering high-quality products and services to help my clients to achieve their business goals.

Part of my current responsibilities at Indeed involve offering consultative advice and support to employers, helping our customers to understand how Indeed can help to meet their talent attraction goals or improve their talent attraction strategy while driving down cost per hire and time to hire.

I also involve myself in sharing best practice, mentoring, supporting new starters, onboarding, training and delivering quarterly reviews for new customers.

I also enjoy supporting charitable organisations with the help of Indeed resources, including coaching long term jobseekers and soon-to-be college leavers to present themselves in the right way in the employment market place.

Work Experience

National Account Manager - Sales and Account Management of Major Accounts

Indeed - London July 2017 to Present

After gaining extensive experience within the online talent attraction industry over the past 18 years, working for leading brands including The Guardian, TotalJobs and LinkedIn, I currently represent the global leader in the online recruitment space- Indeed.com, managing some of our largest UK and Global accounts, and helping enterprise-sized organisations to achieve their talent attraction goals, with the aim to fill all of their positions in a cost-effective manner.

Part of my responsibilities includes offering consultative advice and support to employers, helping our customers to understand how Indeed can lead- or improve their talent attraction strategy, while driving down cost per hire and time to hire.

Internally, I enjoy sharing best practice with my UK and Global colleagues, involve myself in training projects and knowledge sharing, and always promote working collaboratively between departments and regions.

Business Development Manager - Enterprise Accounts

DueDil - London

January 2017 to June 2017

Following an extraordinary journey with my previous employer- LinkedIn, through startup phase, a successful IPO, and the Microsoft acquisition, DueDil stood out as a disruptive business intelligence proposition, with a similar mission and mission that I also wanted to be part of.

In my Senior Business Development role at DueDil, I offer consultative advice to leaders across multiple business functions to demonstrate how DueDil's collaborative platform, that contextualises information for over 40 Million companies, can improve the

way businesses can improve various operations including- Business Development, Sales Operations, Marketing, Research, Credit

Risk, Compliance, Procurement and more

Working on building new business propositions primarily with Enterprise level accounts, and building a robust business case with well known brands, and many more businesses within identified territories. Responsibilities include outbound prospecting, networking, presenting, consultative selling, relationship building, leveraging internal

resources, forecasting and pipeline management.

Additional contributions include supporting new starters, knowledge sharing and product enhancement recommendations.

Reason for leaving: Not the right role for me!

Account Executive - LinkedIn Sales Solutions

LinkedIn

February 2014 to January 2017

EMEA

After 3 years within LinkedIn's largest business line (Talent Solutions), I joined the newest line of business with huge potential-

"Sales Solutions", focusing on the Social Selling sales strategy.

The responsibility of my position of Account Executive within the Sales Solutions business at LinkedIn included offering

consultative advice to business leaders so they can correctly equip their teams with bespoke version of LinkedIn, to be able to do the following:

- Massively increase their team's professional networks to leverage all company connections
- Prioritise their prospects and build bespoke lead lists directly on the LinkedIn platform
- Engage decision-makers directly to shorten sales cycles
- Help to make revenue generating teams more proactive and less reliant on marketing teams
- Discover new opportunities that were not previously easy to identify
- Allow communication with any LinkedIn member
- And much more

LinkedIn has created a premium social selling platform that offers sales professionals the ability to quickly find, qualify and create

new opportunities, and helps Sales Leaders to accelerate the social selling capabilities of their organisation. The corporate tools

help individuals to easily navigate their networks, as well as the connections of their colleagues, to reach more decision makers- directly, and to leverage the power of the world's largest professional network.

Account Executive - Talent Solutions

LinkedIn

August 2010 to February 2014

Following 5 successful years at TotalJobs.com during a huge online recruitment adoption phase, I joined LinkedIn as part of their first 50 employees outside of their USA HQ to help grow the EMEA Talent Solutions business. The entire EMEA business is now employs over 1,500 people.

Over time- I became one of the most tenured Account Executives based in the London office (1 of the 26 Global offices), working closely with HR and Recruitment professionals to advise and implement the most suitable methods to communicate with LinkedIn's active & passive job seekers, and to enable efficient promotion of my client's current and upcoming career opportunities.

I also educate LinkedIn's corporate clients on how to integrate social media professionally within their brands to assist them in becoming an employer brand of choice. Covering geographies including UK, Ireland, Eastern Europe & Africa.

National Account Manager / National Sales Account Manager

Totaljobs.com

December 2007 to September 2010

Promoted to National Account Manager: Consultative sales and ongoing account management of online recruitment solutions to the UK's largest advertising agencies, consultancies & private companies. Territory included Sodexo, Ernst & Young, Burberry, Signet

Group (Ernst Jones, H Samuel, Leslie Davis), Metropolitan Police and many more. Generating new business; taking the client through the full sales cycle from initial call, need find, proposal writing, negotiating, reporting, mentoring new joiners. Other

responsibilities: - Generating account growth - Client meetings (New business presentations, renewal meetings, product training) -

Pipeline management. - Accurate weekly and monthly internal forecasting. Liaising effectively with colleagues, Managers,

Directors, Marketing & Accounts departments Accomplishments: - Promoted from Account Sales Executive to Key Account

Manager then to National Account - Manager within 2.5 years - Exceeding majority of targets set. - Premier point of contact for product knowledge and client strategy queries from colleagues.

Key Account Manager

Totaljobs.com

April 2006 to December 2007

Promoted to Key Account Manager:Consultative sales of online recruitment solutions to the UK's largest advertising agencies,

consultancies & private companies. Territory includes Selfridges, Siemens, Emirates Group, Metropolitan Police. Generating new

business; taking the client through the full sales cycle from initial call, need find, proposal writing, negotiating, reporting. - Client

meetings (New business presentations, renewal meetings, product training) - Pipeline management. - Accurate weekly and monthly

internal forecasting. - Liaising effectively with colleagues, managers, directors, marketing & accounts departments

Accomplishments: - Promoted from Account Sales Executive to Key Account Manager within 18 months.

- Won the "Sales person of the month" prize (out of over 50 Account managers nationwide). - Chosen to represent and pitch for Totaljobs.com's nomination for

"Sales team of the year" presenting to 4 Reed Business Information (RBI) board members.

Sales Account Manager

Totaljobs.com

May 2005 to April 2006

Sales Account Executive Responsibilities Selling online recruitment solutions to consultancies and private enterprises. Pro-actively

developing new business via cold calls, neglected accounts, competitors and leads. Relationship management of existing clients to ensure high retention, up selling, and repeat business. Presenting proposals by email and telecommunication. Negotiating /

Objection handling. Pipeline management. Administration. Meeting and exceeding targets. Accomplishments: During my year in this

position I have met and exceeded 11 out of 12 monthly targets. I reached a £10K billing month from zero billing start figure in the fastest recorded time at Totaljobs.com. Over achieved monthly targets by up to 37%. In the Telesales team, I earned the 2nd

highest bonus payment in Q1 2006. Seen as a senior figure in my department and participate in call coaching/training.

Sales Account Manager

Guardian Media Group March 2000 to May 2005

Responsibilities: Consultative Sales - devising advertising packages, aware of market trends, account management, new business

sales, recruitment & courses advertising, customer care, sales, lead calling. Daily contact with client direct Marketing and HR

departments, as well as agencies including TMP, Barkers, Bartlett Scott Edgar, JWT, Euro RSCG Riley. Accomplishments:

Responsible for Education/Courses territory worth in excess of £500,000 per annum. Delivered 6% increase in territory revenue for period Jan-Dec 2004 (forecast Nov & Dec) compared to Jan-Dec 2003. Earned the highest commission over the last year within the

Guardian's classified recruitment/courses department. (Approx.40 staff). Mentoring / training new starters. Developed good long- term business relationships over the past $4\frac{1}{2}$ years. with major agencies and clients in the Education sector including Oxford

University, Cambridge University, Middlesex University, South Bank University.

Travel Information Adviser

Transport for London - London April 1999 to April 2000

Quickly and efficiently offering information to London 's travellers Achieving KPI's including over 200 calls actioned per day. Detailed

knowledge of the London and South East Travel infrastructure. Customer Service

Sales Executive - Temp

First Telecommunications
December 1998 to April 1999

role only

Sales of calling card credits to new and existing customers.

Trainee Manager

Odeon & UCI Cinemas May 1998 to November 1998

Trainee Manager/Supervisor - Enhanced responsibility within the cinema, co-ordinating staff, stock, accounts, multi-tasking,

coaching, customer care.Reason for leaving - redundancy.

Team Leader

Odeon & UCI Cinemas January 1997 to May 1998

Team Leader, Supervisor at UCI's Flagship cinema - The Empire Leicester Square. Co-ordinating staff, stock management,

concessions, box office accounts, customer care, event management during major film premiers.

Education

Hotel Catering and Institutional Management

Brighton College of Technology 1995 to 1997

Skills

account management (10+ years), Salesforce.com (10+ years), training (10+ years), Sales (10+ years), Business Development (10+ years), Presenting (10+ years), Mentoring (6 years), Account Management (10+ years), Sales (10+ years)

Links

https://www.linkedin.com/in/robertpfox/

Awards

LinkedIn "CLUB" Winner 2015

January 2016

Award granted to top 10% of performers per region / job role / business line

LinkedIn "CLUB" Winner 2011

January 2012

Achieved over 125% of quota in 2011 to become part of LinkedIn's Club- top 10% of achievers.

Customer Centric Selling

May 2017 to Present

Sales Methodology relating to the changing buying and selling process within the enterprise.

4 day course in London facilitated by 6 consultants.

Dale Carnegie Training - High Impact Presentations

June 2018 to Present

For over a century, Dale Carnegie has been improving individual and business performance around the world. While our training techniques continue to evolve, our core principles remain true to a single vision: real transformation begins within.

Sandler Training

April 2018 to Present

Our selling methodology enables salespeople to engage prospects and exchange information with them in an honest, organized, and non-manipulative manner that serves the best interests of both parties.

Additional Information

SKILLS

Salesforce.com, LinkedIn, DueDil, social media platforms, sales, new business, account management, relationship building.

VOLUNTEERINGS

Movember

2011 to 2015

Men's Health Charity UK team organiser

During November each year, Movember is responsible for the sprouting of moustaches on thousands of men's faces in the UK and around the world. The aim of which is to raise vital funds and awareness for men's health, specifically prostate cancer and other cancers that affect men.

I am the UK LinkedIn rep for Movember in 2013 and will organise the fundraising strategy alongside Movember reps and LinkedIn's Marketing team.

Prince's Trust 2012

Volunteer - Training on use of Social Media for their Young Ambassadors

This programme empowers young people to actively participate in the work of The Prince's Trust, engage with public decision making and inspire other young people, while helping to develop leadership and communication skills. Young Ambassadors participate in the programme as volunteers for up to a year.

Department for Work and Pensions (DWP) 2103 to 2014

Training DWP / Jobcentre Advisors and long term jobseekers

Training front line Job Centre staff to understand the benefits of LinkedIn in order to educate jobseekers that they advise- on best practice when using LinkedIn to correctly promote their experience and skills when seeking new employment.

Also presenting and training job seekers at Job Centre London bases.

Planning, developing and delivering training material

Promoting ongoing programme of "Train the Trainer" sessions will continue to occur to empower digital change

RECOMMENDATIONS

On Request See LinkedIn Profile